<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: research | Turing Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/categories/research/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-13T01:55:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://turingmachine.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel German]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards a census of free and open source licenses.]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/towards-a-census-of-used-open-source-licenses/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-12T19:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/towards-a-census-of-used-open-source-licenses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last three years I have been attending the <a href="http://fsfe.org/activities/ftf/network.en.html">European Legal
Network</a> Free Software
Legal and Licensing Workshop.  Because of
the quality of people in attendance this is probably the best
workshop/conference for open source licensing in the world.</p>

<p>This year I presented a talk called <em>Toward a census of free and open
source software licenses</em>.  <!--more-->
Ever since I started working with open
source licenses I have been looking into the issues of what licenses
are more widely used.</p>

<p>The objective of this talk is to describe that a census is not
trivial. There are many factors that can affect the final result. For
this reason it is very important to be very aware of the methodology
behind the census. Otherwise one might be misled by the results.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.man7.org/">Michael Kerrisk</a> from <a href="https://lwn.net/">LWN</a>
was in attendance. As it is customary in this workshop, its discussion
is subject to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chatham_House_Rule">Chatham House
Rule</a>. In a nutshell,
after the meeting you can mention what was discussed, but not who
discussed it.</p>

<p>For that reason Michael requested my permission to write an article at
LWN on my talk. He did a <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/547400/">great
job</a>. It is almost a play-by-play of
the presentation, which I am making available
<a href="/assets/presentations/20130404-amsterdam-licenses-census.pdf">here</a>. Just
a word of advice: the numbers are preliminary. We&rsquo;ll publish
accurate in the very short future.</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
