<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Turing Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-13T02:03:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://turingmachine.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel German]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cellar de Can Roca: the best meal of my life (in the best restaurant of the world)]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/13/cellar-de-can-roca/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-13T00:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/13/cellar-de-can-roca</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I knew I was never going to be able to get a reservation at
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Bulli">elBulli</a> (note the camelCase
:).  But since <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ferran_Adri%C3%A0">Ferran
Adrià</a> decided to close it
I knew I had a chance to one day eat the best restaurant in the
world.</p>

<p>Looking at the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_World's_50_Best_Restaurants">rakings of the best places to
eat</a> <!--more-->
I decided that that restaurant was going to be <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Celler_de_Can_Roca">El Cellar de CanRoca</a>.</p>

<p>Two years before, I was visiting Girona, and decided to walk into the
restaurant (no planning from my part, as usual). Of course, there was
no space :). I asked my friend Jaume, who lives in Girona, to reserve
a table. He did, last year.  And just few days ago, <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2013/apr/29/el-celler-de-can-roca-restaurant">the Cellar was
named the best restaurant in the
world</a>. I
am glad we went when we did. I was told that the day it was announced,
its web site crashed and they got thousands of phone calls.</p>

<p>Was it worth it? You bet. Here are the <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/28858028@N00/sets/72157629963362602/">photos of each of the dishes
we were
served</a>. It
has been, without a doubt, the best meal in my life, and the longest
(we arrived at 1:30 and left at 5:30).</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcelona: champions]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/barcelona-champions/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-12T21:02:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/barcelona-champions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>FC Barcelona is finally champion of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012%E2%80%9313_La_Liga">la
Liga</a>. It is
certainly an accomplishment to have won 4 out of the last 5
championships. Yet this year has a sombre tone. The loss against
<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/may/01/barcelona-bayern-munich-live-mbm-report">Bayern
0-7</a>
left much to be desired. <!--more-->It was not only that they lost, but the
apathy of the team during the second game. It was clear they had given
up.</p>

<p>Has Barça finally reached its zenith? Only time will tell. Sid Lowe, who has a PhD in history, has the one of the <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/blog/2013/may/02/barcelona-bayern-munich-champions-league">best analysis of the what the future might be</a>.</p>

<p>The photo at the right was taken in Feb. 2012, at Camp Nou. Messi almost scored in this play. Look at where he left the players behind him. He is one of a kind.</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards a census of free and open source licenses.]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/towards-a-census-of-used-open-source-licenses/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-12T19:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/towards-a-census-of-used-open-source-licenses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last three years I have been attending the <a href="http://fsfe.org/activities/ftf/network.en.html">European Legal
Network</a> Free Software
Legal and Licensing Workshop.  Because of
the quality of people in attendance this is probably the best
workshop/conference for open source licensing in the world.</p>

<p>This year I presented a talk called <em>Toward a census of free and open
source software licenses</em>.  <!--more-->
Ever since I started working with open
source licenses I have been looking into the issues of what licenses
are more widely used.</p>

<p>The objective of this talk is to describe that a census is not
trivial. There are many factors that can affect the final result. For
this reason it is very important to be very aware of the methodology
behind the census. Otherwise one might be misled by the results.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.man7.org/">Michael Kerrisk</a> from <a href="https://lwn.net/">LWN</a>
was in attendance. As it is customary in this workshop, its discussion
is subject to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chatham_House_Rule">Chatham House
Rule</a>. In a nutshell,
after the meeting you can mention what was discussed, but not who
discussed it.</p>

<p>For that reason Michael requested my permission to write an article at
LWN on my talk. He did a <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/547400/">great
job</a>. It is almost a play-by-play of
the presentation, which I am making available
<a href="http://turingmachine.org/assets/presentations/20130404-amsterdam-licenses-census.pdf">here</a>. Just
a word of advice: the numbers are preliminary. We&rsquo;ll publish
accurate in the very short future.</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is the beginning of the world... again]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/this-is-the-beginning-of-the-world-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-12T17:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013/05/12/this-is-the-beginning-of-the-world-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am tired of web-based blogging. I want to blog when I want, where I
want&mdash;that includes not having an internet connection&mdash;-and don&rsquo;t be
forced to use any specific infrastructure to do it.</p>

<p>Why? because I like my editor. And every time I have to use a
different editing environment I feel trustrated.</p>

<p>So here it goes again&hellip; a reboot of my web site. Well, it just has to
happen every few years&hellip;</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSERC Discovery Grants 2011 in Computer Science]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2011/06/21/nserc-discovery-grants-2011-in-computer-science/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-21T23:50:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2011/06/21/nserc-discovery-grants-2011-in-computer-science</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NSERC has published the results of the <a href="http://www.nserc-crsng.gc.ca/NSERC-CRSNG/FundingDecisions-DecisionsFinancement/ResearchGrants-SubventionsDeRecherche/ResultsGSC-ResultatsCSS_eng.asp?Year=2011">NSERC discovery grant
competition in
2011</a>. NSERC
only published the raw data, so with a little bit of initiative one
can retrieve it and visualize it.</p>

<p>I had several questions about this data&hellip;.</p>

<p> <!--more--></p>

<h3>What is the distribution of grants?</h3>


<p>First, the total amount for Discovery Grants in Computer Science was $5,126,543 per year divided in 202 grants (10 1 year, 1 2 year, 1 3 year and the rest 5 years). They went to 45 different institutions.</p>

<p>Minimum amount was $14k, first quantile $20k, median $24k, average, $25.380k, third quartile $29k, and maximum of $96k (find out below who got it). A Shapiro-Wilk test shows that this distribution appears NOT to be normal (p &lt;&lt; 0.01).</p>

<p>This is the distribution of grants per amount.</p>

<pre>
14,000 46
15,000 1
18,000 1
20,000 39
24,000 43
29,000 34
33,000 19
42,000 7
49,000 6
59,243 1
60,000 1
60,300 1
76,000 1
85,000 1
96,000 1
</pre>


<p>A simple way to visualize this data is tot plot individuals to amounts. Colours reflect the province (click to enlarge):</p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/nserc2011byInd.png"></p>

<p>As it can be seen, there is a fairly uniform distribution across the lowest amounts, with few outliers to the right. Not surprisingly Ontario is the most frequent.
Ontario and BC represent most of the points at the right side. It is surprising to see the absence of Alberta there (its highest is 33k).</p>

<p>Here is a breakdown of the 4 big ones:</p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/ab2011.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/bc2011.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/on2011.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/qc2011.png"></p>

<h3>How do institutions compare?</h3>


<p>I present the results arranged by University. Each vertical column is
a university; they have been sorted by province.  Each point in the
plot is a recipient. The colour of the point represents the type of
grant (1 to 5 years). Most are 5 years, with few being 1 year (what I
call probation grant: they either have faith you can do significantly
better next year, or they are giving you a warning signal).</p>

<p>The median across the country was $24k per year (in the spirit of disclosure mine was $24k).</p>

<p>The boxplots are a simpler way to compare universities and are
overlayed on the data. I have removed outliers from them to avoid
confusion with the data points. Of course, if you have paid attention
to your stats courses you will know that boxplots are good when the
data is normally distributed (which I don&rsquo;t assume it is). Hence their
use in this data is flawed, but they are still useful.</p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/nserc2011byInst.png"></p>

<p>I also got curious who the high fliers were. And below the points are labelled.</p>

<p><img src="http://turingmachine.org/assets/images/2011/nserc2011byInstLabels.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the New York Times mocks me?]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2010/05/25/does-the-new-york-times-mocks-me/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-25T00:22:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2010/05/25/does-the-new-york-times-mocks-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I watched &ldquo;The People vs Larry Flint&rdquo;. One of the scenes is:</p>

<!--more-->




<blockquote><p>Larry: You guys read Playboy?<br/>Friend 1: Well yeah.<br/>Friend 2: Sure.<br/>Jimmy: Yeah.<br/>Larry: Uhmm &#8230; Did you, uh&#8211;excuse me, Baby. Did you enjoy this month&#8217;s article on how to hook up your quadraphonic stereo system?<br/>Friend 3: I think I missed that one.<br/>Larry: And, uh, did you follow their advice on how to make a perfect martini?<br/>Chester: Hey, Larry, c&#8217;mon man, move over.<br/>Larry: Who is this magazine for anyway? I mean, ya know, it&#8217;s like if you don&#8217;t make twenty thousand-plus a year, you don&#8217;t jerk off. Seven million people buying it, and nobody&#8217;s reading it. Gentlemen, Playboy is mocking you!</p></blockquote>


<p>Today I opened the New York Times Travel Magazine, that is included
with the Sunday edition of the paper (yes, I get the paper version). I
found an editorial for the <a href="http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/05/19/geek-chic-power-ranger/">Yves Saint Laurent&rsquo;s Travel Adapter</a>, at a
list price of 450 US. The description reads: &ldquo;Considering how long
stylish travelers have had to cart around less-than-beautiful
electrical doohickeys, it&rsquo;s a wonder that fashion hasn&rsquo;t come to the
rescue sooner.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I wonder if the New York Times is mocking me.</p>

<p>And I haven&rsquo;t even mentioned the ads for many of its products.</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Illiterate: cultural shock]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2009/04/22/illiterate-cultural-shock/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-22T00:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/2009/04/22/illiterate-cultural-shock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got an envelope today, and &ldquo;suddenly it hit me&rdquo;. I am totally
illiterate. I can&rsquo;t even read my own name. I needed 10 minutes using
the wikipedia to understand it (and of course I knew what it was!)</p>

<!--more-->


<p>モラレス ゲルマン ダニエル</p>

<p>I have no idea what it says inside, though .</p>

<p>&mdash;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
