<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: papers | Turing Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/categories/papers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://turingmachine.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-30T10:17:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://turingmachine.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel German]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What effect does Distributed Version Control have on OSS Project Organization?]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013-05-22-what-effect-does-distributed-version-control-have-on-oss-project-organization.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/what-effect-does-distributed-version-control-have-on-oss-project-organization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another paper we published at <a href="http://releng.polymtl.ca/">RelEng: The International Workshop on
Release Engineering</a> is worked mainly by <a href="http://users.encs.concordia.ca/~pcr/">Peter Rigby</a> when we was still
a graduate student: <a href="../assets/pdfs/papers/dmg2013_relengGit.pdf">What effect does Distributed Version Control have on OSS Project Organization?</a></p>

<blockquote>

P. Rigby, E. Barr, C. Bird, P. Devanbu and D. German, “What effect does Distributed Version Control have on OSS Project Organization?”, in <i>The International Workshop on Release Engineering, RELENG 2013</i>, 2013, 29--32.
</blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<p>This paper contrasts the practices of the use of git by the Linux
development team with the use of CVS by FreeBSD (since then FreeBSD
has moved to Subversion).</p>

<p>This is its Bibtex entry:</p>

<pre><code>@inproceedings{dmg2013-relenggit,
  title="{What effect does Distributed Version Control have on OSS Project Organization?}",
  author={Peter Rigby and Earl Barr and Chris Bird and Premkumar Devanbu  and Daniel German},
  booktitle={The International Workshop on Release Engineering, RELENG 2013},
  year={2013},
  month= "May",
  pages = "29--32",
}
</code></pre>

<p>and this its abstract:</p>

<blockquote><p>Many Open Source Software (OSS) projects are
moving form Centralized Version Control (CVC) to Distributed
Version Control (DVC). The effect of this shift on project
organization and developer collaboration is not well understood.
In this paper, we use a theoretical argument to evaluate the
appropriateness of using DVC in the context of two very common
organization forms in OSS: a dictatorship and a peer group. We
find that DVC facilitates large hierarchical communities as well as
smaller groups of developers, while CVC allows for consensus-
building by a peer group. We also find that the flexibility of
DVC systems allows for diverse styles of developer collaboration.
With CVC, changes flow up and down (and publicly) via a
central repository. In contrast, DVC facilitates collaboration in
which work output can flow sideways (and privately) between
collaborators, with no repository being inherently more impor-
tant or central. These sideways flows are a relatively new concept.
Developers on the Linux project, who tend to be experienced DVC
users, cluster around “sandboxes:” repositories where developers
can work together on a particular topic, isolating their changes
from other developers. In this work, we focus on two large,
mature OSS projects to illustrate these findings. However, we
suggest that social media sites like GitHub may engender other
original styles of collaboration that deserve further study.</p></blockquote>

<p>&#x2013;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Future of Continuous Integration in GNOME]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013-05-21-the-future-of-continuous-integration-in-gnome.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/the-future-of-continuous-integration-in-gnome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year is the first edition of <a href="http://releng.polymtl.ca/">RelEng: The International Workshop on Release Engineering</a>.  <a href="http://calcifer.org/">Germán</a> presented our paper <a href="../assets/pdfs/papers/dmg2013_relengGnome.pdf">The Future of
Continuous Integration in GNOME</a>. Its full bibliographic entry is:</p>

<blockquote>

C. Walters, G. Poo-Caamaño and D. M. German, “The Future of Continuous Integration in GNOME”, in <i>The International Workshop on Release Engineering, RELENG 2013</i>, 2013, 33--36.
</blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<p>This paper is a description of the new method to deploy releases in
GNOME in a manner that uses a version control model. The goal is to
make it easy to deploy (and equally important) rollback releases of
the entire desktop.</p>

<p>This is its Bibtex entry:</p>

<pre><code>@inproceedings{dmg2013-relenggit,
  title={The Future of Continuous Integration in GNOME},
  author={Colin Walters and Germán Poo-Caamaño and Daniel M. German},
  booktitle={The International Workshop on Release Engineering, RELENG 2013},
  year={2013},
  month= {May},
  pages = {33--36},
}
</code></pre>

<p>and this its abstract:</p>

<blockquote><p>In Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) projects
based on Linux systems, the users usually install the software
from distributions. The distributions act as intermediaries be-
tween software developers and users. Distributors collect the
source code of the different projects and package them, ready
to be installed by the users. Packages seems to work well for
managing and distributing stable major and minor releases. It
presents, however, various release management challenges for
developers of projects with multiples dependencies not always
available in the stable version of their systems. In projects like
GNOME, composed of dozens of individual components, devel-
opers must build newer versions of the libraries and applications
that their applications depend upon before working in their own
projects. This process can be cumbersome for developers who are
not programmers, such as user interaction designers or technical
writers. In this paper we describe some of the problems that the
current distribution model presents to do continuous integration,
testing and deployment for developers in GNOME, and present
ongoing work intended to address these problems that uses a git-
like approach to the building and deployment of applications.</p></blockquote>

<p>Here is the presentation:</p>

<center>
<iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/21650647" width="476" height="400" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will My Patch Make It? And How Fast? Case Study on the Linux Kernel]]></title>
    <link href="http://turingmachine.org/bl/2013-05-19-will-my-patch-make-it-linux-msr-2013.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://turingmachine.org/bl/will-my-patch-make-it-linux-msr-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today Yujuan presented our paper <a href="../assets/pdfs/papers/dmg2013_msrPatch.pdf">Will My Patch Make It? And How Fast? Case Study on the Linux Kernel</a> at <a href="http://2013.msrconf.org/">MSR 2013</a>. Its full bibliographic entry is:</p>

<blockquote>

Y. Jiang, B. Adams and D. M. German, “Will My Patch Make It? And How Fast? Case Study on the Linux Kernel”, in <i>International Working Conference of Mining Software Repositories, MSR'2013</i>, 2013, 101--110.
</blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<p>The main objective of the paper is to try to determine what are the
characteristics that make a patch being accepted by the Linux
development team.</p>

<p>This is its Bibtex entry:</p>

<pre><code>@inproceedings{dmg2013-relenggit,
  title="{Will My Patch Make It? And How Fast? Case Study on the Linux Kernel}",
  author={Yujuan Jiang and Bram Adams and Daniel M. German},
  booktitle={International Working Conference of Mining Software Repositories, MSR'2013},
  year={2013},
  month= "May",
  pages = "101--110",
}
</code></pre>

<p>and this its abstract:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Linux kernel follows an extremely distributed reviewing and
integration process supported by 130 developer mailing lists and a
hierarchy of dozens of Git repositories for version control. Since not
every patch can make it and of those that do, some patches require a
lot more reviewing and integration effort than others, developers,
reviewers and integrators need support for estimating which patches
are worthwhile to spend effort on and which ones do not stand a
chance. This paper cross-links and analyzes eight years of patch
reviews from the kernel mailing lists and committed patches from the
Git repository to understand which patches are accepted and how long
it takes those patches to get to the end user. We found that 33\% of
the patches makes it into a Linux release, and that most of them need
3 to 6 months for this. Furthermore, that patches developed by more
experienced developers are more easily accepted and faster reviewed
and integrated. Additionally, reviewing time is impacted by submission
time, the number of affected subsystems by the patch and the number of
requested reviewers.</p></blockquote>

<p>The main outcome is that experience plays one of the most important
factors.</p>

<p>&#x2013;dmg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
